<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aurghyadip Kundu</title>
    <link>http://aurghyadip.github.io/tags/elearning/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aurghyadip Kundu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>http://aurghyadip.github.io &amp;copy; 2016 Aurghyadip Kundu</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/tags/elearning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>E-Learning for Indian Students</title>
      <link>http://aurghyadip.github.io/project/deep-learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aurghyadip.github.io/project/deep-learning/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overview&#34;&gt;Overview&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most under rated sector in eLearning is probably where you have to teach kids in regional languages. I was one of the very few students who wanted to study in my mother tongue upto +12 level. And first handely I found out that, there&amp;rsquo;s no help available for the students who are in Regional Language Medium.
My project is to provide students with a video education system, preferably in their regional language (Bengali, Hindi, Oriya, Marathi etc.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As every project has two or three stages, this project also has a couple of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stage-1&#34;&gt;Stage 1:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building the content library as much as possible. That means recording videos from teachers who are willing to contribute and also preparing some materials, like short notes, chapter gists. etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Editing the videos, and planning the courses. Also, carefully curate the contents on a level base so that students won&amp;rsquo;t have any problems understanding the chapters. (This might be one of the most time consuming parts)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Building the website and apps required to deliver the contents. Building the apps require resources and also extensive testing of them. This is also one time consuming step.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stage-2&#34;&gt;Stage 2:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing the contents with actual students and taking feedback from them. How they like the contents and what can be improved to make it more suitable and pleasant.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Testing the platform. Testing the platform on a local network also takes a lot of time, hopefully this will be the &lt;strong&gt;Closed Beta&lt;/strong&gt; stage of the website and the apps.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Releasing an open beta for both the website and the contents, carefully so that the contents doesn&amp;rsquo;t get misused.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Marketing, some marketing is always necessary to make a project successful, just to let parents and students know that we are doing something like this might interest people more and we end up with a better product.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;stage-3&#34;&gt;Stage 3:&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deploying :&lt;/strong&gt; Deploying the webapps and contents on a live server.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Managing :&lt;/strong&gt; Managing the whole finished project requires manpower and is equally hectic. Because problems arise in all projects.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Making the community self sustaining is the ultimate goal of any project.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;The project will be an open source project only if my backers agree to it, otherwise, until and unless I have the money to make the whole project open source, the project will be under a license and a copyright&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
