<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Post-rsses on Aurghyadip Kundu</title>
    <link>http://aurghyadip.github.io/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Post-rsses on Aurghyadip Kundu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>http://aurghyadip.github.io &amp;copy; 2016 Aurghyadip Kundu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 11:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Why Should We Stop Piracy?</title>
      <link>http://aurghyadip.github.io/post/stop-piracy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 02 Oct 2016 11:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aurghyadip.github.io/post/stop-piracy/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Piracy is a big issue in a growing country like India, especially for us developers &amp;amp; creators. I am not only talking about games, I am talking about movies, music, software (and games).
You will obviously ask, why should it hurt us, we are not investing anything making the software and games we are developing, guess what, we are.
We are investing time, our resources, our brain and skills to make those things. And we are also trying to make a living out of it, but when you are downloading them for &amp;lsquo;free&amp;rsquo; from piracy websites (knowingly or unknowingly), it hurts us badly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;me-as-a-pirate&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Me as a pirate?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used to pirate games, in fact, I had one of the biggest collection of pirated games in my school back in 2009-10. Over 20 games (yes it was a big thing back then, to have 20+ games). I remember having titles like, Assassins Creed 1 &amp;amp; 2, NFS etc. But later in college, when I started working as a freelance developer and other things, I understood the value of the things developers put in those games. I understood what it feels like if you work hard and no one pays you. It was one of my biggest demotivator (it still is).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Knowing all those things about piracy and how piracy hurts developers, I felt guilty. But, I did not have enough money to buy all the games I have played. So, I decided to stop playing new games until I paid the debt of the developers of the games I played earlier. It took me 1 year and Rs. 5349.00 to buy all the games I had previously owned. But then I felt happy. I was happy because I spent that much money on games, the feeling that you are supporting the devs is what makes you happy, even more than playing the actual game. Also, I regained my energy to play new games. As it is not always possible to buy a game right away, I wait for a sale in steam for games or go to websites like G2A.com to buy games at a lower price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-you-shouldn-t-pirate-games&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why you shouldn&amp;rsquo;t pirate games!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;ldquo;It (piracy) won&amp;rsquo;t make you Capt. Jack Sparrow&amp;rdquo;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;-Rajkumar Pramanik, Indie game developer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Piracy just hurts the developer. See it this way, your company is making something and people are just stealing it from the storehouse you keep the finished product in. Obviously, your company will go bankrupt in a matter of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now as a fellow Indian, I understand that there is a huge number of problems when buying a game from a website. Number one of them is &lt;del&gt;that your debit card is not supported for international transactions. Steam being the crowned king of this problem, what you can do is, you can either go to G2A.com and buy games, or you can buy steam wallet cards to recharge your steam wallet and buy games directly from steam.&lt;/del&gt; Same things apply for origin and uPlay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Update&lt;/strong&gt; : * Steam now allows Indian customers to buy games through domestic wallet services, such as &lt;strong&gt;PayTM&lt;/strong&gt; and also using domestic credit and debit cards, including &lt;strong&gt;RuPay&lt;/strong&gt; cards. * Origin and uPlay however, does not.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second problem is the internet, now most of us do not have unlimited internet you&amp;rsquo;d say that it takes a lot more GB-s to download a game from steam. Nope, not the case. Downloading a game from piracy website/torrent takes the same amount of GB-s as it does in steam.
Now people with unlimited internet will say that speed is slower when downloading from steam etc. Well, you have to wait to enjoy the full experience and play with your internet connection on. You&amp;rsquo;ll also receive official supports and patches as soon as they release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know you have a lot of reasons why pirating games is not wrong, I won&amp;rsquo;t argue with that. But, if you can buy a game, please do it. It helps the people who make games in making more and more games for you to play. Also, you can always download the game, play sometimes to see if you like the game and then buy it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time. Stay safe. See you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;special-thanks-to&#34;&gt;Special Thanks to -&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rajkumar Pramanik - &lt;a href=&#34;http://hybriona.com/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hybriona Labs&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016 &lt;a href=&#34;http://aurghyadip.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Aurghyadip Kundu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Published on &lt;a href=&#34;http://aurghyadip.com/blog/2016/10/02/why-no-piracy/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Aurghyadip Kundu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>http://aurghyadip.github.io/post/change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aurghyadip.github.io/post/change/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-minor-things&#34;&gt;Some Minor Things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A calm mind is a happy mind. Let the light in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time changes with people or people change with time? Obviously, you’ll go with people change with time, but the reverse is also true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking of some things over and over again for the past two or three weeks. There were some things I were sad about, like people leaving me, but it’s not that bad. Sometimes I feel that we objectified this world too much that we see people as objects, is this good? No, it’s not good. But things change with the flow of time and I am certain that that’ll also change.
I just want to say that I am not sad this time. I have learnt to accept the facts, and I learnt that the hard way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kind of enjoy life now, even without her in my life, I don’t feel an empty place like I used to. I do not have any explanation for why. But I know that she is happy with the life she is leading and I am quite happy with the life I am leading. Yes, finally I can say that my life is not leading me anymore. I know this is a big change but this is a good change. I have a control of things in my life now. Now my decisions matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel kind of new, I have never felt this before. There’s something bad to this also, or maybe good. I pick my friends carefully nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time I loved her. I still see her as one of my friends, I know she doesn’t feel the same, but at least I am free of the guilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of things that cannot be written anywhere. If you are a friend, thank you for your time. And if you are not, then a lot more thanks for going through all the blabbering.
And if it’s you then,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay hungry and stay foolish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016 &lt;a href=&#34;https://personal.aurghyadip.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Aurghyadip Kundu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Published on &lt;a href=&#34;http://personal.aurghyadip.com/change/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Close To The Heart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://aurghyadip.github.io/post/PC_Part_1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aurghyadip.github.io/post/PC_Part_1/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;building-a-2000-pc-and-studio-from-scratch&#34;&gt;Building a $2000 PC (and studio) from Scratch&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As a lot of you might know that I am building a new PC which costs around $2000 (a bit more than that actually). So, here&amp;rsquo;s why and how I am planning to build it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;why&#34;&gt;Why?&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am taking up a project that needs over 45+ hours of video footage processing and rendering. My current PC is a dual core and my current graphics card is also not up to the mark, at this point you might as why I didn&amp;rsquo;t go with a Macbook Pro or iMac in the first place. Well, the answer is easy, a Macbook pro or iMac is not nearly as much as powerful as a custom build $2000 PC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;few-more-things&#34;&gt;Few More Things&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took me almost three months to figure out what I want and how I am going to execute the whole build. I went through a lot of PC Mags and a lot of documentations, benchmarks and price to performance ratios to find what I was looking for in the first place.
You&amp;rsquo;ll get to know what I am talking about in a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;planning&#34;&gt;Planning&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Planning is a crucial part in any kind of thing, if your planning isn&amp;rsquo;t good enough, the whole thing will fall like a house of cards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wanted to build a cheap but powerful computer which performs well even under heavy workload.
Here&amp;rsquo;s my first draft configuration, it&amp;rsquo;s a fairly simple Skylake config.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;i5 6600k&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gigabyte H110M-DS2 DDR4 Motherboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;8 GB Kingston HyperX Fury DDR4 RAM&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;WD Blue 1 TB HDD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Kingston UV300 120GB SSD for OS&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Deepcool Frostwin v2.0 Cooler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Corsair VS550 PSU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;MSI Gamin GTX 1060 6GB&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Circle EPIC gaming cabinet&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you can see, the config is pretty basic, and does well for the price. Although, I was not quite satisfied with it because of the Motherboard, that was almost unacceptable for me, but this draft stayed with me for at least 2 months until I decided to turn the heat up a notch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, that calls for another post. See you soon.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
