<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Aurghyadip Kundu</title>
    <link>http://aurghyadip.github.io/tags/rant/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Aurghyadip Kundu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>http://aurghyadip.github.io &amp;copy; 2016 Aurghyadip Kundu</copyright>
    <atom:link href="/tags/rant/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Change</title>
      <link>http://aurghyadip.github.io/post/change/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://aurghyadip.github.io/post/change/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;some-minor-things&#34;&gt;Some Minor Things&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A calm mind is a happy mind. Let the light in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Time changes with people or people change with time? Obviously, you’ll go with people change with time, but the reverse is also true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have been thinking of some things over and over again for the past two or three weeks. There were some things I were sad about, like people leaving me, but it’s not that bad. Sometimes I feel that we objectified this world too much that we see people as objects, is this good? No, it’s not good. But things change with the flow of time and I am certain that that’ll also change.
I just want to say that I am not sad this time. I have learnt to accept the facts, and I learnt that the hard way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I kind of enjoy life now, even without her in my life, I don’t feel an empty place like I used to. I do not have any explanation for why. But I know that she is happy with the life she is leading and I am quite happy with the life I am leading. Yes, finally I can say that my life is not leading me anymore. I know this is a big change but this is a good change. I have a control of things in my life now. Now my decisions matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel kind of new, I have never felt this before. There’s something bad to this also, or maybe good. I pick my friends carefully nowadays.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once upon a time I loved her. I still see her as one of my friends, I know she doesn’t feel the same, but at least I am free of the guilt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are a lot of things that cannot be written anywhere. If you are a friend, thank you for your time. And if you are not, then a lot more thanks for going through all the blabbering.
And if it’s you then,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Stay hungry and stay foolish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016 &lt;a href=&#34;https://personal.aurghyadip.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Aurghyadip Kundu&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally Published on &lt;a href=&#34;http://personal.aurghyadip.com/change/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Close To The Heart&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
